<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>david cassidy &#8211; Bubblegum Music</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/category/tags/david-cassidy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/</link>
	<description>bubblegum music is the naked truth</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2006 01:00:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Higher They Climb- A Look Back At David Cassidy&#8217;s RCA Debut!</title>
		<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/06/07/the-higher-they-climb-a-look-back-at-david-cassidys-rca-debut/</link>
					<comments>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/06/07/the-higher-they-climb-a-look-back-at-david-cassidys-rca-debut/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[daddykin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2006 01:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[bubblegum university]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david cassidy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mondo Daddykin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mondo daddykin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hi. Even though this was technically David Cassidy&#8217;s fifth &#34;solo&#34; album, many consider it his first because of the circumstances surrounding it. His career to this point was orchestrated by Bell Records. Even the non-Partridge Family records had a similar thread in that they used a lot of the same musicians, songwriters and producers. Now, &#8230; <a href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/06/07/the-higher-they-climb-a-look-back-at-david-cassidys-rca-debut/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The Higher They Climb- A Look Back At David Cassidy&#8217;s RCA Debut!</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi. Even though this was technically David Cassidy&#8217;s fifth &quot;solo&quot; album, many consider it his first because of the circumstances surrounding it. His career to this point was orchestrated by Bell Records. Even the non-Partridge Family records had a similar thread in that they used a lot of the same musicians, songwriters and producers. Now, to my ears, the Bell period will always be the golden period. Wes Farrell&#8217;s production and arrangements, using strings and harpsichords with a pop group, were the perfect complement to David&#8217;s throaty vocals. Let&#8217;s face it, the boy had some chops. Well, when &quot;The Partridge Family&quot; was cancelled in 1974, so ended his contract with Bell. The end of a great era. Now a free agent for the first time in his career, David signed with RCA, who gave him complete control over his output. Cassidy could finally make the rock and roll album that he&#8217;d always wanted to. Released in 1975, this first RCA album is almost a concept album. Titled &quot;The Higher They Climb, The Harder They Fall,&quot; it&#8217;s a tongue-in-cheek jab at his own rise and fall. Cassidy produced the album himself with the help of Bruce Johnston. In addition to Johnston, the players include Beach Boy Carl Wilson, Richie Furay, Jesse Ed Davis, Danny Kortchmar, and Jim Gordon- all session players of rock and roll legend. The Turtles&#8217; Flo and Eddie sing backup on a couple of songs, and there&#8217;s even a comedy skit with Phil Austin of The Firesign Theatre! A fine, underappreciated album that tends to be forgotten with time. I&#8217;m sharing mp3&#8217;s of this classic album at my blog,&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;<a href="http://mondodaddykin.blogspot.com/">http://mondodaddykin.blogspot.com/</a>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Check it out! daddykin</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/06/07/the-higher-they-climb-a-look-back-at-david-cassidys-rca-debut/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Partridge Family &#8211; Sound Magazine</title>
		<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/23/soundmagazine/</link>
					<comments>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/23/soundmagazine/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2006 20:21:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[artists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bobby hart]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[david cassidy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[partridge family]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ron garmon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[rupert holmes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tony romeo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wes farrell]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Partridge FamilySound Magazine(Bell, 1971) Since you&#8217;ve tried everything else, why not a fierce, impeccable pop concept album about jism pressure? Released just before The Partridge Family&#8217;s second season left the egg, Sound Magazine, like predecessors The Partridge Family Album and Up To Date was produced by Wes Farrell, written by songwriters then resident in &#8230; <a href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/23/soundmagazine/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The Partridge Family &#8211; Sound Magazine</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Partridge Family<br /><em>Sound Magazine</em><br />(Bell, 1971)</p>
<p>Since you&rsquo;ve tried everything else, why not a fierce, impeccable pop concept album about jism pressure? </p>
<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B00004VW4U/ref=nosim/bubblegumbook"><img border="0" alt="Medium Image" src="http://images.amazon.com/images/P/B00004VW4U.01.MZZZZZZZ.jpg" /></a> Released just before The Partridge Family&rsquo;s second season left the egg, <em>Sound Magazine</em>, like predecessors <em>The Partridge Family Album </em>and<em> Up To Date</em> was produced by Wes Farrell, written by songwriters then resident in popdom&rsquo;s upper ether (Rupert Holmes, Bobby Hart, Tony Romeo) performed by L. A. session wizards like Hal Blaine (drums) and Michael Melvoin (keys), backup sung by the Love Generation and, not quite incidentally, vocalized by TV mom Shirley Jones and her brilliantly lovelorn son, David Cassidy. Here, then, is product&#8211;that base, yet tasty, ore upon which the record industry built its fortunes. Presold to a gigantic preteen audience, there is no conventional rock critic excuse at all for this album&rsquo;s emotional sweep and delicacy. So much the worse for convention and rock criticism.</p>
<p>Cassidy&rsquo;s excuse is ambition. On previous outings, Farrell sped up David&rsquo;s voice to make the star (then in his late teens) sound adolescent. The effect was that of a constipated chipmunk fleeing a series of catgut holocausts. The son of Broadway dynamo Jack Cassidy and Hollywood musical-comedy star Shirley Jones, David fit poorly the then-emerging model of instant pop star, since nothing was above his station, and had every expectation of a long career once the TV show closed. A song-cycle about star-isolation and busted love affairs was a rare perfect fit of commerce and art.</p>
<p>Finally, there&rsquo;s the scarcely believable, yet unmistakable intent that post-Beatles preteens might respond to a sophisticated, cleverly-wrought whole. The beautiful boy&rsquo;s sore heart, expressed with magnificent brio in &ldquo;Rainmaker,&rdquo; &ldquo;One Night Stand&rdquo; and &ldquo;I Woke Up In Love This Morning&rdquo; provided kids with tantalizing glimpses of adult miseries they couldn&rsquo;t wait to have for their very own. (Ron Garmon, from the book <a target="_blank" href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0415969980/ref=nosim/bubblegumbook"><em>Lost in the Grooves: Scram&#8217;s Capricious Guide to the Music You Missed</em></a>) </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/23/soundmagazine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
