<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>bubblegum university mondo daddykin archies riverdale archives &#8211; Bubblegum Music</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/category/tags/bubblegum-university-mondo-daddykin-archies-riverdale-archives/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/</link>
	<description>bubblegum music is the naked truth</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 May 2006 05:37:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>THE ARCHIES-  THE RIVERDALE ARCHIVES!!</title>
		<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/24/the-archies-the-riverdale-archives/</link>
					<comments>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/24/the-archies-the-riverdale-archives/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[daddykin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2006 05:37:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[bubblegum university mondo daddykin archies riverdale archives]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mondo Daddykin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Calling all fans of The Archies and Ron Dante! Did you know there is a wealth of unreleased material from The Archies at their peak period? About 95% of the songs played on &#34;Archie&#8217;s Funhouse&#34; (the third season of the TV cartoon) were unreleased pop gems penned primarily by Neil Goldberg, working under Jeff Barry &#8230; <a href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/24/the-archies-the-riverdale-archives/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">THE ARCHIES-  THE RIVERDALE ARCHIVES!!</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Calling all fans of The Archies and Ron Dante! Did you know there is a wealth of unreleased material from The Archies at their peak period? About 95% of the songs played on &quot;Archie&#8217;s Funhouse&quot; (the third season of the TV cartoon) were unreleased pop gems penned primarily by Neil Goldberg, working under Jeff Barry at the time (1970-71). Along with the dance-of-the-week numbers, we&#8217;re talking close to 50 rarities. When I first heard these on TV, I was about 10 years old. I had no concept of the value of a &quot;non-LP B-side.&quot; It&#8217;s like a treasure hidden away for the truest fans. That&#8217;s what I equate the &quot;Funhouse&quot; songs and the dances to, and why I consider it the Holy Grail of Archies music. This is not some lame later incarnation of the band, but the same awesome musicians that gave us &quot;Sugar Sugar.&quot; To Beatles fans (which I am one of the biggest in the whole wide universe), it&#8217;s the equivalent of finding several unreleased studio albums lying in a warehouse&#8230;they&#8217;re in their PRIME and Ron Dante&#8217;s voice shines like the sun itself. Well, you may ask, &quot;How can I hear these?&quot; I put together a VHS video compilation of these clips that I sell on eBay (just look under my member name, daddykin, for availability). Then, I culled the audio of the songs off the videotapes and transferred it to a CD that I call &quot;The Riverdale Archives.&quot; I share this CD with you freely at my blog,&nbsp;<a href="http://www.mondodaddykin.blogspot.com/">http://www.mondodaddykin.blogspot.com/</a> Please check it out. You won&#8217;t be disappointed. daddykin </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/24/the-archies-the-riverdale-archives/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
