<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>the spinners &#8211; Bubblegum Music</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/category/tags/the-spinners/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/</link>
	<description>bubblegum music is the naked truth</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 03:50:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Tommy James &#038; The Shondells</title>
		<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/tommy-james-the-shondells/</link>
					<comments>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/tommy-james-the-shondells/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 03:50:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[artists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bill holmes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ellie greenwich]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff barry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[joan jett]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mad mike metro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ritchie cordell]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the spinners]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tommy James &#038; The Shondells by Bill Holmes Jeff Barry and Ellie Greenwich reportedly wrote the song in twenty minutes as a filler track that became the b-side of a failed single. The Spinners, then trolling the bus tour circuit, had it in their repertoire to help get a few people out on the dance &#8230; <a href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/tommy-james-the-shondells/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Tommy James &#038; The Shondells</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Tommy James &#038; The Shondells<br />
by Bill Holmes</p>
<p>Jeff Barry and Ellie Greenwich reportedly wrote the song in twenty minutes as a filler track that became the b-side of a failed single.  The Spinners, then trolling the bus tour circuit, had it in their repertoire to help get a few people out on the dance floor.  Tommy James, nee Jackson, grew up near the Michigan/ Indiana border and would often check out the Chicago and Detroit bands that came through the area.  And when James needed another song to cut with his band the Shondells for a local DJ named Jack Douglas, he remembered the dumb riff that caught his ear.  Having only heard the song once, James didn&#8217;t even know the words, so he made some up and mumbled the others.  It was just a riff after all.  Douglas released the song on his Snap Records label, and after the usual brief local buzz, the record faded away.</p>
<p>That was until Mad Mike Metro, a Pittsburgh DJ, found the record in a bargain bin and started playing it repeatedly on his show, until it eventually soared all the way to number one in the area.  By the time he was able to track James down, some local entrepreneur had already bootlegged it and sold thousands of copies.  To capitalize on the success of the single, James quickly tried to reassemble the original band, who had all graduated from school and started to go their separate ways.  In one of the classic bad career moves of rock </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/tommy-james-the-shondells/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
