<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>laura pinto &#8211; Bubblegum Music</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/category/tags/laura-pinto/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/</link>
	<description>bubblegum music is the naked truth</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2006 19:23:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Ron Dante&#8217;s Lost Singles- Forgotten Gems From The Voice Of The Archies!</title>
		<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/06/11/ron-dantes-lost-singles-forgotten-gems-from-the-voice-of-the-archies/</link>
					<comments>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/06/11/ron-dantes-lost-singles-forgotten-gems-from-the-voice-of-the-archies/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[daddykin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 11 Jun 2006 19:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[archies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bubblegum university]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[laura pinto]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mondo Daddykin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mondo daddykin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ron dante]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hi. As a huge Archies fan and avid record collector, I set out to find as many tracks as I could that featured the golden pop voice of Ron Dante. Many of you may know that in addition to the wonderful Archies catalog, Ron was also the voice of &#34;Tracy&#34; by The Cufflinks. Well, his &#8230; <a href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/06/11/ron-dantes-lost-singles-forgotten-gems-from-the-voice-of-the-archies/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Ron Dante&#8217;s Lost Singles- Forgotten Gems From The Voice Of The Archies!</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi. As a huge Archies fan and avid record collector, I set out to find as many tracks as I could that featured the golden pop voice of Ron Dante. Many of you may know that in addition to the wonderful Archies catalog, Ron was also the voice of &quot;Tracy&quot; by The Cufflinks. Well, his pop music history goes much further and deeper than that. While researching his career on the internet a few years ago, I stumbled into a website called &quot;Laura Pinto&#8217;s Ron Dante Fan Pages.&quot; This chick had written extensive articles on Dante, including a discography that blew me away! While I had found a few old singles at yard sales and flea markets, Laura had amassed a collection so thorough that she was providing the man himself with copies of his own lost songs! Well, after a few e-mail exchanges, Laura and I became friends and started to trade tracks and videos back and forth. While the CD that I&#8217;m offering at MONDO DADDYKIN does not give you everything from our collections, it is definitely the cream of the crop of the rarities. These 32 tracks are all compiled from Laura&#8217;s singles. She had me transfer them for her and Ron awhile back, and has graciously given me permission to post them. We tried to avoid songs that are available commercially or for download from Ron&#8217;s official site. Ron Dante&#8217;s work was often released under the name of a &quot;ghost group&quot; or a pseudonym. The CD starts with his very first record, Ronnie Dante&#8217;s &quot;Little Lollipop&quot; from 1963! Laura Pinto also runs several other awesome sites dedicated to bubblegum music and classic oldies, and contributes invaluable articles to the pop community on a regular basis. Laura, bless you for sharing your collection with us. Hopefully, this will give our readers a new appreciation of the pop giant that is Ron Dante. I am sharing mp3&#8217;s of many of these rarities at my blog,&nbsp; <a href="http://www.mondodaddykin.blogspot.com/">http://www.mondodaddykin.blogspot.com/</a> Check it out!! daddykin</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/06/11/ron-dantes-lost-singles-forgotten-gems-from-the-voice-of-the-archies/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
