<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>underground comix &#8211; Bubblegum Music</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/category/tags/underground-comix/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/</link>
	<description>bubblegum music is the naked truth</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 May 2006 09:33:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Sopwith Camel</title>
		<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/02/the-sopwith-camel/</link>
					<comments>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/02/the-sopwith-camel/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2006 09:33:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[artists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kama sutra]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[neo vaudeville]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[san francisco]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[underground comix]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[victor moscoso]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Sopwith Camel by Kim Cooper Although they recorded for Kama Sutra, and their sole hit had the traditional double-barreled name, the Sopwith Camel was emphatically not a bubblegum band.&#160; What they were were mid-sixties San Francisco misfits, a little too weird for that scene, who scored a big hit single with a New York &#8230; <a href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/02/the-sopwith-camel/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The Sopwith Camel</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B000DNVL0C/ref=nosim/bubblegumbook"><img src="http://images.amazon.com/images/P/B000DNVL0C.01.MZZZZZZZ.jpg" alt="Medium Image" /></a></p>
<form action="http://buybox.amazon.com/o/dt/assoc/handle-buy-box=asin" method="post"><input type="hidden" name="asin.B000DNVL0C" value="1" /><input type="hidden" name="tag-value" value="bubblegumbook" /><input type="hidden" name="tag_value" value="bubblegumbook" /><input type="image" name="submit.add-to-cart" value="Buy from Amazon.com" src="http://rcm-images.amazon.com/images/G/01/associates/add-to-cart.gif" alt="Buy from Amazon.com" border="0" /></form>
<p>The Sopwith Camel <br />by Kim Cooper</p>
<p>Although they recorded for Kama Sutra, and their sole hit had the traditional double-barreled name, the Sopwith Camel was emphatically not a bubblegum band.&nbsp; What they were were mid-sixties San Francisco misfits, a little too weird for that scene, who scored a big hit single with a New York producer and broke up so quickly that they barely finished their album. &nbsp;</p>
<p>Nevertheless, people continue to lazily lump the Sopwith Camel in with the bubblegummers, and not entirely without reason.&nbsp; Most Kama Sutra acts had hardcore kiddie appeal, and the Camel was no exception.&nbsp; Their charming, retro songs would go over nicely during kindergarten quiet time.&nbsp; And like all the best bubblegum bands, they were brought to New York at a producer&rsquo;s behest, only to have everything go wrong.&nbsp; If not truly of the genre, we&rsquo;re willing to peg them as bubblegumesque.</p>
<p>Band leaders Peter Kraemer and Terry MacNeil met in a bookshop in 1966.&nbsp; Terry was a student at the San Francisco Art Institute, and Peter was from a bohemian Virginia City family&mdash;although he&rsquo;d moved away before the Red Dog Saloon became hepcat-central during the Charlatans&rsquo; tenure.&nbsp; Drummer Norman Mayell had played with Mike Bloomfield and Charlie Musselwhite in Chicago before moving west to hanging out with the Kesey crowd.&nbsp; Martin Beard was British, seventeen, and the bassist, natch.</p>
<p>Kraemer had been living with Chet Helms in the Haight when the latter was trying to launch a new group.&nbsp; Names were bandied about, and Kraemer&rsquo;s suggestion was mocked for being &ldquo;trite and dumb&rdquo;&mdash;so Helms&rsquo; group became Big Brother and the Holding Company (sheesh) and Kraemer remembered Sopwith Camel when he formed his own band.</p>
<p>Things started happening for the Camel once occasional bassist Bobby Collins sent a demo tape including &ldquo;Hello, Hello&rdquo; to Lovin&rsquo; Spoonful producer Erik Jacobsen.&nbsp; Jacobsen&mdash;a visionary who had left his bluegrass band after hearing the Beatles, and who collaborated with John Sebastian to forge a distinctly American brand of folk&rsquo;n&rsquo; roll &mdash;smelled a hit with this light-hearted, retro ditty, and invited the group out to New York.&nbsp; They signed with Kama Sutra, making them one of the earliest SF bands with a record deal.&nbsp; They&rsquo;d never quite fit in with the other San Francisco bands, and &ldquo;selling out&rdquo; to an East Coast producer ensured that this remained the case.&nbsp; Nonetheless, the Victor Moscoso cover art on their album was one of the first instances of mass exposure for an underground cartoonist from the SF scene.</p>
<p>Sure enough, &ldquo;Hello, Hello&rdquo; made the Top 10.&nbsp; Their album, recorded as the group was disintegrating in unfriendly Manhattan, is a delightful old-timey idyll mixing moments of whimsy with some nifty oddball rock&rsquo;n&rsquo;roll.&nbsp; Kraemer&rsquo;s flapper vocal stylings and romantic lyrics are well-served by the organ grinding band.&nbsp; You can see why Jacobsen liked them&mdash;they&rsquo;re much closer to the Spoonful in their sense of play and wit than to any of the super-serious Bay Area bands.&nbsp; After recording a couple of Levis ads, the band split up.&nbsp; They reformed around 1971, prompted by Burger King&rsquo;s use of &ldquo;Hello, Hello&rdquo; as a commercial jingle, and went on to record one well-reviewed space-rock LP with Jacobsen, The Miraculous Hump Returns from the Moon (Reprise, 1973).</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/02/the-sopwith-camel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
