<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>sugar bears &#8211; Bubblegum Music</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/category/tags/sugar-bears/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/</link>
	<description>bubblegum music is the naked truth</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 05:05:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Discography of known cereal box records</title>
		<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/discography-of-known-cereal-box-records/</link>
					<comments>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/discography-of-known-cereal-box-records/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 05:05:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[archies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bobby sherman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cardboard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cereal box records]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[discographies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jackson 5]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[monkees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sugar bears]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Here&#8217;s a useful appendix from the bubblegum book&#8230; but do please note: I&#8217;m not a dealer in cereal box records, and I can&#8217;t tell you the value of yours. I recommend you go to eBay.com, get an account, and &#8220;search completed auctions&#8221; for &#8220;cereal box&#8221; and the name of the artist to see what they&#8217;re &#8230; <a href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/discography-of-known-cereal-box-records/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Discography of known cereal box records</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here&#8217;s a useful appendix from the bubblegum book&#8230; but do please note: I&#8217;m not a dealer in cereal box records, and I can&#8217;t tell you the value of yours. I recommend you go to eBay.com, get an account, and &#8220;search completed auctions&#8221; for &#8220;cereal box&#8221; and the name of the artist to see what they&#8217;re selling for, or click on the link below to see live auctions. Have you got questions not answered on this page? So sorry, I don&#8217;t know the answer either!</p>
<p>Discography of known cereal box records compiled by Kim Cooper with help from Don Charles, Michael Cumella, James Porter, David Smay, Vern Stoltz and especially Lisa Sutton</p>
<p>One of the most delightful of bubblegum artifacts is the cardboard cereal box record, cut raggedly from the back of the box by an impatient child, or carefully by a helpful adult. At the peak of the bubblegum era, it was possible to compile an excellent library of lo-fi gems by most of the major kinderpop artists, provided a kid could talk his family into eating the right cereals.</p>
<p>These records have interesting precedents in the annals of American marketing. Among the earliest records offered as cereal premiums was a series of six fairy tales with follow-along books put out by Post Raisin Bran in 1949. These mail-away offers included &#8220;Beauty and the Beast&#8221; and &#8220;The Golden Goose.&#8221; In 1954, General Mills released a series of at least eight different 78-rpm children&#8217;s songs that were actually imprinted on Wheaties cereal boxes. These included such proto-gum faves as &#8220;Take Me Out to the Ball Game, &#8221; &#8220;Three Little Fishes,&#8221; and &#8220;On Top of Old Smokey.&#8221; On the same boxes kids were also invited to send in a quarter to receive Wheaties-produced red-orange vinyl 78-rpm albums.</p>
<p>Vintage Scooby Doo Mystery Machine T-shirt</p>
<p>Vintage Scooby Doo Basketball T-shirt</p>
<p>Vintage Shaun Cassidy T</p>
<p>	And more vintage T-shirts and iron-ons from RetroDuck.com</p>
<p>Around the same time there were at least two Walt Disney&#8217;s Mousketeer Records, cardboard cereal box 78s that featured Mickey, Donald and Goofy singing &#8220;I&#8217;d Rather Be I&#8221; and the title character performing &#8220;Donald Duck&#8217;s Song.&#8221; In 1964, buyers of Kellogg&#8217;s Corn Flakes could mail in a quarter and a back-of-the-box coupon to receive a 7&#8243; long-playing record with the story and theme song from Hanna-Barbera&#8217;s animated movie Hey There, Yogi Bear.</p>
<p>In perhaps the strangest twist of all, around 1967 the pre-bubblegum Shadows of Knight released their great &#8220;Potato Chip&#8221; single-which was only available inside packages of Fairmont Potato Chips!</p>
<p>Bubblegum-era cereal box records typically recycled the same design for between three and five possible songs in each series. The song titles appeared on the label, and a kid could pick which box they wanted by the identifying numeral stamped onto the cardboard.</p>
<p>The following bubblegum cereal box record discography is as complete as we could make it in a full year of research. Once a kid cut the disk off the identifying box, these babies became an archivist&#8217;s nightmare.</p>
<p>THE ARCHIES</p>
<p>Archies design #1 (Big Ethel, Dilton, Moose, Midge, Reggie, Sabrina, Archie, Veronica, Betty and Jughead dancing against a yellow background) (Honey Comb/ Kirshner) 1. You Make Me Wanna Dance 2. Catchin&#8217; Up On Fun 3. Jingle Jangle 4. Love Light</p>
<p>Archies design #2/version A (Archie, Betty, Jughead, Hot Dog, Reggie and Veronica holding the black ring in the center of the record) (cereal unknown/ Kirshner) 1. Archie&#8217;s Party 2. You Know I Love You 3. Nursery Rhyme[s] 4. Jingle Jangle.&#8221;</p>
<p>Archies design #2/version B (Archie, Betty, Jughead, Hot Dog, Reggie and Veronica holding the black ring in the center of the record) (cereal unknown/ Kirshner) 1. You Make Me Wanna Dance 2. Catching Up On Fun 3. Jingle Jangle 4. Love Light</p>
<p>Archies design #3 (The Archies playing their instruments with Hot Dog panting, no track list or numbering) (Post<br />
Super Sugar Crisp/ Kirshner) [Michael Cumella reports that the concept for this disk was developed by Harry<br />
Gorman of Allied Creative Services in Port Jervis, NY]</p>
<p>Tracks include (but may not be limited to) the following: #. Sugar, Sugar #. Hide &#8216;N&#8217; Seek #. Boys And Girls #.<br />
Feelin&#8217; So Good (SKOOBY-DOO) #. Bang-Shang-A-Lang #. (Archie&#8217;s Theme) Everything&#8217;s Archie.</p>
<p>BANANA SPLITS</p>
<p>There were two mail-order vinyl 7&#8243; EPs offered by Kellogg&#8217;s cereal; only the first track on each is taken from<br />
the band&#8217;s LP.</p>
<p>Kellogg&#8217;s 34578: &#8220;The Tra-La-La Song (One Banana, Two Banana)&#8221; &#8220;That&#8217;s The Pretty Part Of You&#8221; b/w &#8220;It&#8217;s A<br />
Good Day For A Parade&#8221; &#8220;The Very First Kid On My Block.&#8221;</p>
<p>Kellogg&#8217;s 34579: &#8220;Doin&#8217; The Banana Split&#8221; &#8220;I Enjoy Being A Boy (In Love With You)&#8221; b/w &#8220;The Beautiful Calliope&#8221; &#8220;Let<br />
Me Remember You Smiling&#8221;</p>
<p>JACKSON 5</p>
<p>Jackson 5 design #1; (Rice Krinkles/ Motown) (Photo of band standing off to the left, stacked vertically-yellow<br />
label, blue tint to grooves) 1. ABC 2. I want you back 3. I&#8217;ll bet you 4. Darling dear 5. Maybe tomorrow</p>
<p>Jackson 5 design #2/ version A (Alpha Bits/ Motown) (song titles on a cartoonish flower shaped background-no<br />
mention of the J5, blue tint to grooves) 1. Sugar Daddy 2. Goin&#8217; Back To Indiana 3. Who&#8217;s Loving You</p>
<p>Jackson 5 design #2/ version B (Alpha Bits/ Motown) (song titles on a cartoonish flower shaped background-no<br />
mention of the J5, blue tint to grooves) 1. I&#8217;ll Be There 2. Never Can Say Goodbye 3. Mama&#8217;s Pearl</p>
<p>JOSIE &#038; THE PUSSYCATS</p>
<p>(1970) These were mail away 45s. Up to four were offered for 35</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/discography-of-known-cereal-box-records/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
