<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>hudson brothers &#8211; Bubblegum Music</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/category/tags/hudson-brothers/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/</link>
	<description>bubblegum music is the naked truth</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2006 23:05:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>So You Are A Star- Remembering The Hudson Brothers</title>
		<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/06/09/so-you-are-a-star-remembering-the-hudson-brothers/</link>
					<comments>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/06/09/so-you-are-a-star-remembering-the-hudson-brothers/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[daddykin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2006 23:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[bubblegum university]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hudson brothers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mondo Daddykin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mondo daddykin]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hi. Remember The Hudson Brothers? They had a great primetime variety series on CBS-TV in the summer of 1974. &#34;The Hudson Brothers Show&#34; did so well as a summer replacement series that CBS put in a quick order for a Saturday morning version to debut the following month. Becoming &#34;The Hudson Brothers Razzle Dazzle Show,&#34; &#8230; <a href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/06/09/so-you-are-a-star-remembering-the-hudson-brothers/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">So You Are A Star- Remembering The Hudson Brothers</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hi. Remember The Hudson Brothers? They had a great primetime variety series on CBS-TV in the summer of 1974. &quot;The Hudson Brothers Show&quot; did so well as a summer replacement series that CBS put in a quick order for a Saturday morning version to debut the following month. Becoming &quot;The Hudson Brothers Razzle Dazzle Show,&quot; the boys graced our TV sets through 1975. Mark, Brett, and Bill had been making records since 1972, originally under the name &quot;Hudson.&quot; By the time their second album was picking up speed, Casablanca Records scurried to put together a soundtrack album to tie in with their TV success. &quot;Hollywood Situation,&quot; from 1974, offers songs heard in both TV series as well as a comedy skit called &quot;The Adventures of Chucky Margolis,&quot; one of the more popular segments from both series. This album, along with the TV push, scored them a hit with the Beatlesque &quot;So You Are A Star.&quot; Even as their TV career was nearing its end, they scored a big hit in 1975 with &quot;Rendezvous.&quot; This is from their Rocket Records debut called &quot;Ba-Fa.&quot; As an FYI, I should mention that Bill is the father of actress Kate Hudson (he was married to Goldie Hawn at the time). I haven&#8217;t heard much from Brett since, but Mark has been busy collaborating with, producing, and touring with Ringo Starr in recent years. Their songs were all solid AM pop material, mostly penned by the three brothers themselves. I&#8217;m sharing mp3&#8217;s of &quot;Hollywood Situation&quot; and &quot;Ba-Fa&quot; at my blog, <a href="http://www.mondodaddykin.blogspot.com/">http://www.mondodaddykin.blogspot.com/</a> &nbsp;Check it out! daddykin</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/06/09/so-you-are-a-star-remembering-the-hudson-brothers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
