<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>1910 fruitgum co. &#8211; Bubblegum Music</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/category/tags/1910-fruitgum-co/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/</link>
	<description>bubblegum music is the naked truth</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 May 2006 07:24:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Kasenetz-Katz and Their Super-Duper Rock &#038; Roll Kavalcade</title>
		<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/03/kasenetz-katz-and-their-super-duper-rock-roll-kavalcade/</link>
					<comments>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/03/kasenetz-katz-and-their-super-duper-rock-roll-kavalcade/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2006 07:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[1910 fruitgum co.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buddah]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[james porter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ohio express]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[producers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[super k]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kasenetz-Katz and Their Super-Duper Rock &#038; Roll Kavalcade by James Porter Of all the revered record producers with a hitmaking streak and an identifiable sound, the Kasenetz-Katz duo has to be among the most underrated. Garage freaks worship at the altar of Ed Cobb (Standells, Chocolate Watchband), Ken Nelson (Buck Owens, Wanda Jackson) is a &#8230; <a href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/03/kasenetz-katz-and-their-super-duper-rock-roll-kavalcade/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Kasenetz-Katz and Their Super-Duper Rock &#038; Roll Kavalcade</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kasenetz-Katz and Their Super-Duper Rock &#038; Roll Kavalcade<br />
by James Porter</p>
<p>Of all the revered record producers with a hitmaking streak and an identifiable sound, the Kasenetz-Katz duo has to be among the most underrated.  Garage freaks worship at the altar of Ed Cobb (Standells, Chocolate Watchband), Ken Nelson (Buck Owens, Wanda Jackson) is a big name with the retro-country set, the outer-space sonatas of Joe Meek (Blue Men, Tornadoes) have a strong cult, and Phil Spector is probably the only non-performing producer who has his own section in record stores.  But even though Jerry Kasenetz and Jeff Katz produced their share of radio-active hits in &#8217;68-&#8217;69, most rock historians regard them as a footnote.  In The New Book Of Rock Lists by Dave Marsh and James Bernard, producers as diverse as Lee </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/03/kasenetz-katz-and-their-super-duper-rock-roll-kavalcade/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Lost Feature: Tommy Roe, Brian Hyland, Tommy James &#038; the Shondells</title>
		<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/the-lost-feature-tommy-roe-brian-hyland-tommy-james-the-shondells/</link>
					<comments>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/the-lost-feature-tommy-roe-brian-hyland-tommy-james-the-shondells/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 09:45:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[1910 fruitgum co.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[brian hyland]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[buddy holly]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[domenic priore]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[shelly kidd]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tommy james]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tommy roe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An Appreciation of Tommy Roe, Brian Hyland, Tommy James &#038; the Shondells and other primordial examples of bubblegum by Domenic Priore in conversation with Shelly Kidd Domenic Priore: We were trying to figure out what separates the British Invasion groups from the &#8217;60s Garage Punk bands in America that followed, and when you said &#8220;they &#8230; <a href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/the-lost-feature-tommy-roe-brian-hyland-tommy-james-the-shondells/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The Lost Feature: Tommy Roe, Brian Hyland, Tommy James &#038; the Shondells</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An Appreciation of Tommy Roe, Brian Hyland, Tommy James &#038; the Shondells and other primordial examples of bubblegum<br />
by Domenic Priore in conversation with Shelly Kidd</p>
<p>Domenic Priore: We were trying to figure out what separates the British Invasion groups from the &#8217;60s Garage Punk bands in America that followed, and when you said &#8220;they warped it with Chili Dogs&#8221; that pretty much says it all</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/the-lost-feature-tommy-roe-brian-hyland-tommy-james-the-shondells/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The 1910 Fruitgum Company</title>
		<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/the-1910-fruitgum-company/</link>
					<comments>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/the-1910-fruitgum-company/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 04:28:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[1910 fruitgum co.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bill holmes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bo gentry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kasenetz-katz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mark gutkowski]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ritchie cordell]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The 1910 Fruitgum Company by Bill Holmes When today]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 1910 Fruitgum Company<br />
by Bill Holmes</p>
<p>When today</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/the-1910-fruitgum-company/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>1910 Fruitgum Co. Liner Notes</title>
		<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/1910-fruitgum-co-liner-notes/</link>
					<comments>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/1910-fruitgum-co-liner-notes/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 04:04:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[1910 fruitgum co.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bo gentry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bobby bloom]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kasenetz-katz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kim Cooper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mark gutkowski]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ritchie cordell]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Click to purchase The Best Of The 1910 Fruitgum Company THE 1910 FRUITGUM CO. by Kim Cooper A thick pink strain of bubblegum music came oozing out of the world&#8217;s AM radios between 1967 and 1969, giving little kids something to pound their Mickey Mouse spoons about, and making critics groan. If you followed it &#8230; <a href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/1910-fruitgum-co-liner-notes/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">1910 Fruitgum Co. Liner Notes</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><P><font face="Geneva, Arial, Helvetica, san-serif" size="2"><A HREF="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/B00005AQ0H/ref=nosim/bubblegumbook%20">Click to purchase The Best Of The 1910 Fruitgum Company</A></font></P><br />
THE 1910 FRUITGUM CO. by Kim Cooper</p>
<p>A thick pink strain of bubblegum music came oozing out of the world&#8217;s AM radios between 1967 and 1969, giving little kids something to pound their Mickey Mouse spoons about, and making critics groan. If you followed it back to the source you&#8217;d find New York City, and the studios rented by independent producers Jerry Kasenetz and Jeff Katz. Under their supervision a revolving crew of bands, session players and writers knocked out giddy pop songs that mixed garage band riffs and nursery school rhyme schemes with deliciously catchy results.</p>
<p>By late 1967, Kasenetz and Katz were anxiously seeking hitmaking bands that could be paired up with writers in their Super K Productions stable. They&#8217;d already mined the teen clubs of central Ohio to come up with the Music Explosion, Ohio Express (originally Sir Timothy &#038; the Royals) and Lemon Pipers (Ivan &#038; the Sabres), but their next discovery would be found much closer to home.</p>
<p>Supposedly Jeff Katz&#8217; dad met several members of Jeckell &#038; the Hydes (previously known as the Lower Road, and the Odyssey) in a Linden, New Jersey diner, and passed their number along to his son; later, the producers heard them play at a house party. Kasenetz and Katz flipped over Mark Gutkowski&#8217;s boyish voice, and quickly signed the band to a production contract. With a little work, they&#8217;d become the third act in the mega-selling Buddah bubblegum triumvirate that included the Ohio Express and Lemon Pipers.</p>
<p>Of course that retro garage band name had to go, and &#8220;1910 Fruitgum Co.&#8221; fit right in with the other sugary Kasenetz and Katz confections. PR legend has it that rhythm guitarist Jeckell named the Fruitgums from an old gum wrapper found either in a suit pocket or an attic trunk (possibly both).</p>
<p>The 1910 Fruitgum Co. had their first hit with the immortal &#8220;Simon Says,&#8221; a song K&#038;K had been trying to place for some time. The kindergarten game lyrics set to a chugging garage rock organ riff set the stage for much of their future activity. They quickly established themselves as the most childlike of the bubblegum bands, their singles filled with babyish games and infantile alliteration. Album tracks revealed more adult themes, sometimes disturbingly fused with references to a loved one&#8217;s yummy candy sweetness. With these guys, you never knew if they were about to kiss a girl or take a bite!</p>
<p>But even the singles were more suggestive than they appeared on first glance. The lyrics of &#8220;1-2-3 Red Light&#8221; are less a schoolyard game than the sound of a boy wearing down his sweetie&#8217;s resistance through constant begging, with the threat of a break up if she doesn&#8217;t put out.</p>
<p>Every time I try to prove my love<br />
1-2-3 Red Light, you stop me&#8230;<br />
If you stop me again<br />
That&#8217;s when we might end<br />
So please don&#8217;t refuse</p>
<p>And in the sorta-psychedelic &#8220;1910 Cotton Candy Castle,&#8221; the promise of candy seems to carry a distinctly phallic subtext when Mark croons: &#8220;Here comes the Lollipop Man in his goody ship Lollipop/ all aboard for lollipop land where the lovin&#8217; never stops.&#8221;</p>
<p>For their first few (most bubblegummy) albums, the 1910 Fruitgum Co. was officially made up of the old Jeckell &#038; the Hydes lineup. This was Mark Gutkowski (vocals/ organ), Frank Jeckell (vocals/ rhythm guitar), Floyd Marcus (vocals/ drums), Steve Mortkowitz (bass) and Pat Karwan (vocals/ lead guitar). But sidemen were always being called in to play on K&#038;K productions, and there&#8217;s some controversy about who played on what. An intermediate lineup was Gutkowski with Chuck Travis (vocals/ lead guitar), Larry Ripley (vocals/ bass/ horn), Bruce Shay (vocals/ percussion), and Rusty Oppenheimer (vocals/ drums). Less than two years on, the hard rocking Hard Ride was the work of Jimmy Casazza (vocals/ drums/ percussion), Ralph Cohen (trumpet), Jerry Roth (vocals/ sax/ clarinet/ flute), Don Christopher (vocals/ guitar), Richie Gomez (vocals/ guitar) and Pat Soriano (vocals/ organ/ piano). Since K&#038;K owned the band name, anyone they wanted could &#8220;be&#8221; the 1910 Fruitgum Co.</p>
<p>Mark Gutkowski&#8217;s singing was the constant on most things released under the 1910 Fruitgum Co. name, but their #5 hit &#8220;1, 2, 3 Red Light&#8221; was supposedly Gutkowski backed by Vinnie Poncia, Pete Anders and guys from the touring version of session group the Tradewinds (&#8220;New York&#8217;s a Lonely Town&#8221;)-while other sources claim that Gutkowski wasn&#8217;t present at all, and the vocals for this song and &#8220;Goody Goody Gumdrops&#8221; were by &#8220;Gumdrops&#8221; co-writer Billy Carl.</p>
<p>Personnel matters aside, whoever the 1910 Fruitgum Co. were, they made monster bubblegum records throughout their short career, and the kids loved them. A vintage press release offers the tantalizing claim that their fans threw so much bubblegum (chewed and otherwise) during performances, that a little man had to sweep it up after every show. We also learn a thing or two about the original band members. Frank Jeckell (21) is the oldest, and the one who makes sure the others behave. He digs country music and golf. Pat Karwan (19) surfs, hates diets and airplanes, and chews a lot of gum. He sometimes uses the pen name Scaramuche Quackenbush. Mark Gutkowski (18) likes girls, steak and onions and sheepskin rugs, and hates barbershops and oatmeal. Steve Martkowitz (19) studied art in Paris, and is the silent type. Floyd Marcus (19) is always late, wants to be a great songwriter, hates shredded coconut and likes girls and sports car racing. Such nice boys.</p>
<p>&#8220;Indian Giver,&#8221; recorded with the middle Fruitgum lineup, proved to be the final Top 10 bubblegum smash for Buddah, first charting in January 1969. The song gives no sign that the power of bubblegum music was diminishing, and that hypnotic tom-tom beat can still stir the blood of tykes and their elders to this day. Master gumsters Bobby Bloom, Bo Gentry and Ritchie Cordell wrote this politically insensitive gem, while Bloom and Gentry wrote the Fruitgum&#8217;s final charting hit, &#8220;Special Delivery,&#8221; and produced both with Cordell.</p>
<p>Like most fads, bubblegum faded out after two years, but the Fruitgum Co. wasn&#8217;t quite ready to call it quits. Kasenetz and Katz gleefully told Roctober magazine&#8217;s James Porter that the final version of the band nearly got a plum gig at the Fillmore East, a hall far too hip to stoop to booking has-been bubblegummers. But an unlabeled test pressing of the heavier Hard Ride album impressed a booker sufficiently that a show was briefly offered, then immediately retracted when the ruse was revealed.</p>
<p>With that, the 1910 Fruitgum Co. retired, never to be seen again.</p>
<p>Thanks to Carl Cafarelli, Bill Holmes and James Porter.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/1910-fruitgum-co-liner-notes/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kasenetz-Katz Singing Orchestral Circus</title>
		<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/kasenetz-katz-singing-orchestral-circus/</link>
					<comments>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/kasenetz-katz-singing-orchestral-circus/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2006 03:52:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[1910 fruitgum co.]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[artists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff katz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jerry kasenetz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kasenetz-katz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[music explosion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ohio express]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[producers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kasenetz-Katz Singing Orchestral Circus by Bill Pitzonka 1968 was a banner year for bubblegum]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kasenetz-Katz Singing Orchestral Circus<br />
by Bill Pitzonka</p>
<p>1968 was a banner year for bubblegum</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/04/26/kasenetz-katz-singing-orchestral-circus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
