<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>mamas and papas &#8211; Bubblegum Music</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/category/tags/mamas-and-papas/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/</link>
	<description>bubblegum music is the naked truth</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 May 2006 06:47:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Lovin&#8217; Spoonful</title>
		<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/05/the-lovin-spoonful/</link>
					<comments>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/05/the-lovin-spoonful/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2006 06:47:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[artists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bob dylan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cass elliot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Gary Pig Gold & Carl Cafarelli]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[john b. sebastian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mamas and papas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[zalman yanovsky]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[by Gary Pig Gold &#160; Excuse me, but I think America had already produced a more-than-competent &#8220;answer&#8221; to that great big British Invasion quite some time before the Byrds and &#8220;Mr. Tambourine Man&#8221; ever reared their jingle-jangled heads. I speak of the undeniably brilliant, once and forever Happy Hit Machine known as the Lovin&#8217; Spoonful. &#8230; <a href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/05/the-lovin-spoonful/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The Lovin&#8217; Spoonful</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>by Gary Pig Gold <br /> &nbsp;</p>
<p> Excuse me, but I think America had already produced a more-than-competent &ldquo;answer&rdquo; to that great big British Invasion quite some time before the Byrds and &ldquo;Mr. Tambourine Man&rdquo; ever reared their jingle-jangled heads. </p>
<p> I speak of the undeniably brilliant, once and forever Happy Hit Machine known as the Lovin&rsquo; Spoonful. </p>
<p> With long tangled roots deep within folk, jug-band music and the blues, this quartet somehow squeezed from its diverse musical lineage the deceptively simple brew they called, quite perfectly, Good-Time Music.&nbsp; In fact the band&rsquo;s first monumental hit, &ldquo;Do You Believe In Magic,&rdquo; was no less than a musical manifesto &ndash; a Top Forty Call-To-Arms even! &#8212; which instantly launched a solid three-year run of immense yet ** always ** innovative international hits. </p>
<p> The story began in New York City on the momentous night of February 9, 1964.&nbsp; At 8PM, on the corner of 53rd and Broadway, Ed Sullivan was introducing those four guys from Liverpool to a rightfully astonished nation.&nbsp; A couple of miles downtown, three under-employed folk singers named Cass Elliot, Zalman Yanovsky and John B. Sebastian were among the 73 million most definitely tuned in.&nbsp; Then and there, all three decided to form their very <em>own</em> rock &lsquo;n&rsquo; roll combos, and after various incarnations and permutations &ndash; not to mention a recreational side <em>trip</em> or two (all documented in song and dance, by the way, within the verses of the Mamas &amp; Papas&rsquo; &ldquo;Creeque Alley&rdquo;) &#8212; it was John and Zal who, when the haze had cleared, were wowin&rsquo; em every night from the stage of the Night Owl Caf&eacute; with co-conspirators Steve Boone and Joe Butler in tow.&nbsp; Taking their name from a Mississippi John Hurt tune, the Lovin&rsquo; Spoonful soon numbered among their most loyal fans Phil Spector (who lobbied, unsuccessfully as it transpired, to be their producer), local boy Bob Dylan (getting ready to plug <em>himself</em> in at that very time), and a would-be Andrew Loog Oldham name of Erik Jacobsen, who quickly signed the band to the brand new Kama Sutra label.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<p> Of course, you <em>can</em> safely call the Spoonful &ldquo;bubblegum&rdquo; (as just one look at lead guitarist Zal Yanovsky, a human cartoon if ever there was one, will attest), but they were in fact one of those rare bands who dared to &ndash; and were capable of &ndash; supplying a goodly amount of Substance with their Pop.&nbsp; Certainly hits such as &ldquo;Did You Ever Have To Make Up Your Mind?&rdquo; and especially the landmark &ldquo;Summer In The City&rdquo; laid the keyboard-crafted game-plan for much Super K gumness to come, plus the band&rsquo;s on-stage penchant for brightly-striped T-shirts and over-sized cowboy hats make even the 1989 Musical Marching Zoo&lsquo;s stagewear seem downright demure by comparison.&nbsp; In fact, so potent was the Spoonful&rsquo;s aura of goofy, glorious mayhem that they were briefly being considered for a starring role in their very own weekly television series!&nbsp; Lucky for Davy Jones though, the Spoonful seemed content instead to make a cameo appearance in &ndash; not to mention write the score for &#8212; Woody Allen&rsquo;s first (and by far greatest) film, 1966&rsquo;s Japanese Bond spoof &ldquo;What&rsquo;s Up, Tiger Lily?&rdquo;&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<p> Yet beneath all this day-glo zaniness, the band remain widely respected and revered more for their musicianship, and in particular Sebastian&rsquo;s songwriting, than they are for their happy-go-lucky mugging across <em>Hullabaloo</em> and <em>Shindig</em>.&nbsp; Tragically though, the luck began to run out in 1967 following the controversial arrest and subsequent removal of Yanovsky back to his home and native Canada (where, until his above-untimely demise in 2002, he continued cookin&rsquo; up storms as owner and proprietor of the legendary Chez Piggy restaurant);&nbsp; by 1969, all that seemed to remain of those once Good Times was the disturbing sight of John Sebastian, clothed from head to toe in tie-dyed denim, babbling about far-outness on the stage of the Woodstock Music and Art Fair.&nbsp; Yikes! </p>
<p> Nevertheless, the Lovin Spoonful remain a very vital part of 1960&rsquo;s American Pop, and their early breakthrough period provided a veritable musical <em>and</em> visual blueprint upon which all manner of Bubblegum was shortly thereafter concocted.&nbsp; And as if that alone wasn&rsquo;t ample legacy enough, may I now remind you all that the late, so great Zally&rsquo;s 1968 solo album &ldquo;Alive And Well In Argentina&rdquo; just has to be one of the drop-down, most magnificent works of bubble-fried art <em>ever</em> created by man or beast, and as such should immediately be searched out and purchased by each and every person reading these here words. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/05/the-lovin-spoonful/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
