<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>mike batt &#8211; Bubblegum Music</title>
	<atom:link href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/category/tags/mike-batt/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/</link>
	<description>bubblegum music is the naked truth</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 07:53:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.7.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Wombles</title>
		<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/04/the-wombles/</link>
					<comments>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/04/the-wombles/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2006 07:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[artists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bill pitzonka]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[captain kangaroo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[elizabeth beresford]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mike batt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[producers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[songwriters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[by Bill Pitzonka In 1974, the British charts were awash in glam rockers and toothy teen idols. Rising somewhat surprisingly above this glittery sea to claim Music Week&#8217;s Top Singles Act of the Year was a group of furry, burrow-dwelling litter-gatherers]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>by Bill Pitzonka</p>
<p>In 1974, the British charts were awash in glam rockers and toothy teen idols.  Rising somewhat surprisingly above this glittery sea to claim Music Week&#8217;s Top Singles Act of the Year was a group of furry, burrow-dwelling litter-gatherers</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/04/the-wombles/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Producers and Impresarios</title>
		<link>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/02/producers-and-impresarios/</link>
					<comments>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/02/producers-and-impresarios/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[kim]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2006 09:51:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[gary usher]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gary zekley]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeff barry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jonathan king]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kasenetz and katz]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mike batt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[producers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false"></guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Bubblegum is the story of songwriter-producers&#8212;makers of shiny sounds.&#160; The villains in many rock legends, these are people who saved their innocence for their musical sentiments and never did anything so stupid as to sign away their publishing.&#160; Firing inept drummers, replacing lead singers, they ruthlessly worked the system to make it pop.&#160; But here &#8230; <a href="https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/02/producers-and-impresarios/" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Producers and Impresarios</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Bubblegum is the story of songwriter-producers&mdash;makers of shiny sounds.&nbsp; The villains in many rock legends, these are people who saved their innocence for their musical sentiments and never did anything so stupid as to sign away their publishing.&nbsp; Firing inept drummers, replacing lead singers, they ruthlessly worked the system to make it pop.&nbsp; But here we also find gentle studio geeks with a genius for engineering, child prodigies, cheerful tunesmiths in love with the game, the insane pace, the charts. </p>
<p> We&rsquo;re conscious of legendary recording sessions with Phil Spector and Brian Wilson, George Martin facilitating Sgt. Pepper, Aretha&rsquo;s first epochal piano chord in Memphis or Hendrix pulling together layers of sonic strata on Electric Ladyland.&nbsp; Still, our sense of the studio&rsquo;s place in Rock Mythology remains peripheral.&nbsp; Only serious music fans know the names James Jamerson or Hal Blaine, while even the most casual listener knows their work.&nbsp; Bubblegum, like Disco, like Motown, like much of Nashville today, exists primarily within a studio culture of session players and songwriter-producers.&nbsp; This particular hyphenate ought to be better known than singer-songwriters&mdash;it&rsquo;s the economic trigger for the whole recording industry.&nbsp; Why?&nbsp; Because both songwriters and producers collect royalties, and if you double up your credits on a hit record you&rsquo;re raking in some serious chump change. &nbsp;</p>
<p> Reading these interviews we&rsquo;re struck by the canniness and audacity of non-writers Kasenetz and Katz piggybacking bizarre studio goofs onto the b-sides of sure hits to collect songwriting checks.&nbsp; Or Jonathan King&rsquo;s shameless talent for converting fads into pop hits.&nbsp; But we also delight in Jeff Barry building up the drum track for &ldquo;Be My Baby&rdquo; one mallet tap at a time, or Mike Batt living in a Womble suit for a week before setting those characters in song.</p>
<p> Here you find tricksters and hipsters, songwriters and songbirds, studio tans and golden ears.<br /> &nbsp;<br /> West Coast Pop anticipated bubblegum&rsquo;s methods, blurred the lines between music for sale and music that sells, influenced the sound of bubblegum and provided the pool of creators that presided over its cartooniest era.</p>
<p> As the man who squeezed Brian Wilson&rsquo;s vision into an LP&rsquo;s worth of slot-car racing songs and gave voice to Big Daddy Roth&rsquo;s model kits, Gary Usher&rsquo;s influence can&rsquo;t be overstated.&nbsp; Bubblegum&rsquo;s splendid tradition of completely fictitious bands starts at the Brill Building, but achieves a cheesy genius in the Weird-Ohs, the Super Stocks, the Hondells, and the Revells.&nbsp; Though his busiest period predates bubblegum&rsquo;s onset by several years, Gary Usher laid out the entire bubblegum blueprint before it had a name.&nbsp; He recorded musically and lyrically upbeat music with a steady core of studio musicians under a variety of ghost band names, commissioned for a visual medium (substitute Beach Movies for TV here).&nbsp; Whereas most bubblegum makers went into commercial jingles after their bubblegum careers, Usher brazenly turned a Honda promotion into a masterstroke of pop genius (&ldquo;Little Honda&rdquo;).</p>
<p> Gary Zekley perfectly encapsulates the West Coast studio scene, swallowing not-so-disparate sub-genres like surf, sunshine pop, bubblegum and psych pop in one gulp.&nbsp; Most of his East Coast peers simply considered themselves pop songwriters with little concern for marketing categories.&nbsp; Zekley&rsquo;s fluid career cautions against leaning too heavily on genre distinctions.&nbsp; You can assign the Fun and Games, Yellow Balloon and the Clique to different bins, but the same talent clearly penned &ldquo;The Grooviest Girl in the World,&rdquo; &ldquo;How Can I Be Down&rdquo; and &ldquo;Superman.&rdquo;</p>
<p> Oftentimes the supporting players provide a better window into a scene than the big names.&nbsp; Carol Connors found a niche in the L.A. scene, fronting Beach Bunny bands for Gary Usher and co-writing some tunes.&nbsp; Carol&rsquo;s &ldquo;Yum Yum Yamaha&rdquo; does more to clarify the seamless fusion of surf, bubblegum and commercial jingles that defined west coast pop than any five books about the Beach Boys.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://www.bubblegum-music.com/2006/05/02/producers-and-impresarios/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
